Guide to the Niku Arbabi Zine Collection, 1999-2007 and undated RL.00050
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Niku Arbabi Zine collection
1999-2007 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Arbabi, Niku
RL.00050
0.5 Linear Feet
Arbabi is an artist, DJ, writer, filmmaker, and zinester from Durham, NC and Austin, TX. She is the author of several craft and activist zines, including Radical South, Chicks Rock, and Polaroid-Celluloid. The collection consists of 34 zines (27 titles, produced between 1999 and 2007) collected by Arbabi. Eight of the zine titles in the collection were written or co-written by Arbabi. The majority of zines in the collection focus on either craftmaking and the do-it-yourself lifestyle or women's personal stories, including stories of abuse. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
34 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Niku Arbabi Zine Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Biographical Note
Arbabi is an artist, DJ, writer, filmmaker, and zinester from Durham, NC and Austin, TX. She is the author of several craft and activist zines, including Radical South, Chicks Rock, and Polaroid-Celluloid.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of 34 zines (27 titles, produced between 1999 and 2007) collected by Niku Arbabi. Eight of the zine titles in the collection were written or co-written by Arbabi. Arbabi acquired several of the zines in her collection from Parcell Press, a zine distro located in Richmond, Va. Zines authored by Arbabi that were purchased directly from Parcell Press are also included in this collection. The zines in the collection focus on craftmaking and the do-it-yourself lifestyle; feminist activism; and women's personal stories, including stories of abuse. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Feminism -- United States; Fan magazines; Comic books, strips, etc.; Abused women -- United States; Self-publishing; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Mail art -- United States; Handicraft -- United States; Young women -- United States -- Social life and customs; Women -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Underground press publications -- United States; Arbabi, Niku, collector.; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Aubergine, undated (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Houston, TX
- brainscan, no. 19, 2002 December (Box 1)
  Portland, OR: Microcosm Publishing
- Broken Hipster, no. 2, undated (Box 1)
- Chicks Rock, 2004 July (Box 1)
  Durham, NC
- document one, undated (Box 1)
  Portland, OR: Youth in Revolt
- Doris, no. 13, undated (Box 1)
  Asheville, NC
- Doris, no. 14, undated (Box 1)
- Doris, no. 14, undated (Box 1)
- Doris: D.I.Y. Antidepression Guide, no. 15, undated (Box 1)
- Doris, no. 16, 2000 Summer (Box 1)
- Doris, no. 18, undated (Box 1)
- Emily: A Zine by a Mom and Daughter, undated (Box 1)
  Philadelphia, PA: Sweet Candy Distro
- Geraniums and Bacon, no. 2, undated (Box 1)
  Bella Razor Press
- Hard Knox, undated (Box 1)
  Acworth, GA: Sweet Candy Distro
- I Hear You Like Stories!, no. 1, 2004 July (Box 1)
  Gorham, NH: Stalker Distro
- Imaginary Life, no. 5, [2003] (Box 1)
  Portland, OR: Pony Boy Press
- In Your Room, no. 8, undated (Box 1)
  Bellingham, WA
- In Your Room: "at the corner of dude and party," no. 11, undated (Box 1)
- Marked For Life / No Better Voice, no. 2 / 30, 2006 February (Box 1)
  Philadelphia, PA and Ferndale, MI: Sweet Candy Distro
- Mine: An Anthology of Reproductive Rights, no. 2, undated (Box 1)
  Philadelphia, PA
- More Signs You Do a Zine, no. 2, 1999 June (Box 1)
  Havre de Grace, MD: Leeking Inc.
- My Birthday Trip to the Outer Banks, 2006 March (Box 1)
  Durham, NC: The Ephemeral Mailbox Museum
- On Zines: North Carolina, 2004 November (Box 1)
- Polaroid Celluloid, 2005 February (Box 1)
- Postal Curiosities & Delights, 2007 October (Box 1)
  Austin, TX: The Ephemeral Mailbox Museum
- Radical South, undated (Box 1)
- Radical South: Resources & Stories for Radical Spaces, People, Events, and Groups in the South, undated (Box 1)
- Scrappy: A Crafty Zine for Scrappy People, no. 1, undated (Box 1)
- she rose again, [2002] (Box 1)
- Spectacular Specula: An Activist Dyke Discusses Self-care, Queer Reproductive Rights, and Her Os, undated (Box 1)
  Washington, DC
- Squad Set, undated (Box 1)
- The Down-and-dirty, Do-it-yourself Moviemaking Guide for Film Girls and Video Vixens, undated (Box 1)
- The Remainder of Zero: What's Left Behind: A Story in Parts, undated (Box 1)
  Portland, OR
- The Science, no. 22, 2005 Spring (Box 1)
  San Francisco, CA